<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <ttl>1440</ttl>
        <title>Zachary Kai</title>
        <link>https://zacharykai.net/</link>
        <description>Offbeat, queer, 20-something, curiosity enthusiast, and traveler.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <image>
            <url>https://zacharykai.net/assets/zk_icon.png</url>
            <title>Zachary Kai</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/</link>
        </image>
        <atom:link href="https://zacharykai.net/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>

        <item>
            <title>Minds Within Mine | Zachary Kai</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/notes/mwm</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 04:51:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://zacharykai.net/notes/mwm</guid>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                <h1>Minds Within Mine</h1>
                <p class="postmeta"><strong>Published</strong>: 11 Apr 2025 | <strong>Updated</strong>: 11 Apr 2025</p>
                <p id="top"></p>
                <p>I've always wondered what my characters say about me. Couple that with there are so many folks living in my head, it's difficult to keep track... Why don't I write about them here?</p>
                <p>Once I've breathed a little life into them, I'll figure out where to place them.</p>
                <p>Of course, an obligatory spoiler warning for my past and future fiction. And discussions of unhinged worldbuilding and thought-through violence (because these are the stories I write.)</p>
                <p>First, there's Mara. She's been in my life since 2019 when I devised her earliest version. In her trilogy (The Mara Files, of course) she's a forty-five-year-old wrongly convicted criminal, disgraced war hero, disabled veteran, and former peacekeeping unit captain.</p>
                <p>A woman of strong morals and even stronger opinions, she's intimidating in both stature and presence, with little time for the petty concerns of others. Including the basic social niceties. She's jarring personality, blunt and stubborn (her name means bitter), yet she's guided by justice.</p>
                <p>And this is where her redemption lies. Even if she doesn't know it yet.</p>
                <p>Sharing Mara's story is Ishali, a young reptilian of indeterminate age and origins, yet he seems far more versed in the criminal underworld than Mara. Patient to her need for instant results and gentle to her brashness, it appears he was born in the wrong world. Weighed down by something never explained, he carries himself in even ridiculous situations with indescribable grace.</p>
                <p>Ardent and Cal are Mara's two former lieutenants and forever at odds with each other. Despite working with them for over ten years, only when they're forced together in extraordinary circumstances does Mara learn to work with them. They're both troublemakers, though Ardent is a powerful artificial entity and Cal is an overgrown ball of grump with horns.</p>
                <p>Will they cooperate without her guidance?</p>
                <p>It appears the answer will always be no.</p>
                <p>A standalone book, languishing since 2023, contains a trio so intertwined they might as well run in each other's blood. As Isadora puts it: "She's the thread binding our stories together, you're the catalyst, and I'm the chronicler. The sensemaker."</p>
                <p>Isadora is a compulsive journaler. Over twenty-four hours without putting pen to paper, and her mind unravels. Like me. Except where she heed the warning, I allow myself to become distracted by shiny new objects galore. An anxious, sensitive soul, she's an excellent diplomat, yet unappreciated and overlooked.</p>
                <p>She draws her meaning in life from her two beloved friends.</p>
                <p>One is Gwen, a young woman who's more metal than flesh, rebuilt after an accident that left her scarred and on life's last legs. Devoted to her principles and her people, she'd rather watch the galaxy burn than compromise either. A woman of few words and expressions.</p>
                <p>And 'you'? That's Xander, engineered as part of a coalition on creating a species of super beings, combining the best qualities of human and alaraph, an avian people. People heralded this experiment as a savior in the ongoing war, and yet... Of thousands of tests, only he survived.</p>
                <p>A mess of anatomies cobbled together, a body neither humanoid nor avian, too heavy for the sky and too light for the ground. It should've been a disaster.</p>
                <p>Instead, he and Gwen, in their sheer raw power and dogged determination, turned the tide of the war. Only one came back from the brink. Or so they thought.</p>
                <p>When he resurfaces, he's unrecognizable. Scars cover his once pristine skin like golden threads snatched from the skin, body devoid of jewelry and markings, wings rebuilt and made retractable.</p>
                <p>They all think they know what happened. Now they have to see what's next.</p>
                <p>The rest remain mere sketches, outlines, and concepts.</p>
                <p>Ariki, a man with an eyepatch and secrets even I'm not privy to. Kieran, a boy more powerful than the empress but is her subordinate than take over her empire. Marcus Irris, living under an assumed name for so long, he forgets who he is.</p>
                <p>And more to come. Ideas are ever-present. Just waiting to be discovered.</p>
                <p>Do people reside within you? Who are they? What are they like?
                </p><p>•--♡--•</p>
                <p class="essentials"><strong>Copy &amp; Share</strong>: <a href="/notes/mwm">zacharykai.net/notes/mwm</a></p>
                            <p class="essentials">
                <strong>Reply Via</strong>:
                <a href="mailto:hi@zacharykai.net">Email</a> | 
                <a href="/guestbook">Guestbook</a> |
                <a href="/unoffice-hours">UnOffice Hours</a> | 
                <a href="https://webmention.io/zacharykai.net/webmention" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Webmention</a>
            </p>
                <p class="essentials"><strong>Statistics</strong> → Word Count: 708 | Reading Time: 332</p>
                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>The Unexpected Ambassador | Zachary Kai</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/notes/icmar25</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://zacharykai.net/notes/icmar25</guid>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                <h1 class="p-name">The Unexpected Ambassador</h1>
                <p class="postmeta"><strong>Published</strong>: <time class="dt-published" datetime="2025-03-21">21 Mar 2025</time> | <strong>Updated</strong>: <time class="dt-updated" datetime="2025-03-21">21 Mar 2025</time></p>
                <p id="top" class="p-summary"><em>This is a submission for the <a href="https://lifeofpablo.com/blog/self-expression-indieweb-carnival-march-2025" class="u-in-reply-to h-cite">March 2025 IndieWeb Carnival on Self-Expression</a> hosted by <a href="https://lifeofpablo.com/">Pablo Morales</a>.</em></p>
                <p>To exist is to explain. Especially if you occupy multiple intersecting identities. As a queer, neurodivergent, homeschooled, overseas raised, intermediate Spanish speaking, twenty-something who folks mistake as twelve... I have some experience with that phenomena.</p>
                <p>I could regale you with the ridiculous situations I've experienced (many I caused), the comments and questions...</p>
                <p>Why should I add to the world's negativity when enough for a thousand worlds exists in my head? Instead, I'll highlight the opportunities this gives me.</p>
                <p>As you may glean, I'm convincing myself as much as reassure you. So it goes.</p>
                <p>When I first traveled overseas, I was introduced to the concept of being 'an ambassador' for my nationality. As an Australian passport holder, I'm proud of the continent and its people, and critical of its failings. Isn't everything a duality? I visited many out-of-the-way places, interacting with folks who'd never met an Australian before.</p>
                <p>Folks dismiss first impressions as meaningless, but when your exposure to something is rare... They mean everything. So for people who meeting an Australian was an anomaly... Wasn't there an opportunity? To give these folks a good perspective?</p>
                <p>Every culture has a stereotype, unfounded, yet persistent, most people abhor. For me, it's 'shrimps on the barbie' tied with 'everything will kill you.' I've never seen <em>anyone</em> grill shrimps. Most folks call it a barbeque (derived from an Indigenous South American language anyway.) As for all creatures being out to get you... Leave them alone, they'll let you be!</p>
                <p>An example of how powerful first impressions are: a man bewildered on meeting an Australian who didn't swear every second word. Granted, I cuss <em>now</em>, but it didn't compute that some Australians didn't use expletives.</p>
                <p>Perception isn't the full reality, but it might as well be.</p>
                <p>In every interaction, on the continent and elsewhere, I aim to be empathetic and earnest. If I'm the only Australian a person will ever meet, I want to be a kind one.</p>
                <p>The same goes for every facet of my identity.</p>
                <p>As for my obscure hobbies, from having a website for fun, to zine-making, and fanfiction... These aren't for everyone, of course, but for the right person? Transformative! How can it become so for these folks if they don't know about it?</p>
                <p>Shakespeare's words are immortal for a reason. "There's nothing either good or bad, but thinking makes it so."</p>
                <p>Next time something about my existence intrigues or confuses someone, may I see it as a sneaky way to plant a positive impression in someone's mind.</p>
                <p>•--♡--•</p>
                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Writing Sparks</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/notes/sparks</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 06:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://zacharykai.net/notes/sparks</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>Writing Sparks</h1>
            <p class="postmeta"><strong>Published</strong>: 1 Mar 2025 | <strong>Updated</strong>: 2 Mar 2025</p>
            <p id="top"></p>
            <p>The blank page is a gentle terror. These prompts may make it less so. Even... fun? Enjoy.</p>
            <ul>
            <li><strong>25-Word Universe:</strong> Paint a vivid world within twenty-five words.</li>
            <li><strong>A Small Delight Catalog:</strong> Celebrate life's tiny joys and secret pleasures.</li>
            <li><strong>A Letter From Your Desk:</strong> What might your surface say about your inner life?</li>
            <li><strong>An Unspoken Gratitudes List:</strong> Write about wonders you've never appreciated aloud.</li>
            <li><strong>A Seed's Poem:</strong> Describe patience, darkness, and anticipation through the eyes of a seed underground.</li>
            <li><strong>A Postcard From Yesterday's Tomorrow:</strong> Write greetings from the futures imagination once promised you.</li>
            <li><strong>Alphabetic Fables:</strong> Let each sentence start with sequential letters from A to Z.</li>
            <li><strong>Fairy Tale Footnotes:</strong> What essential details did they leave out?.</li>
            <li><strong>Instructions For Reading Dreams:</strong> Write a manual for translating your sleeping life into words.</li>
            <li><strong>Invisible Character Sketch:</strong> Describe someone without mentioning appearance at all.</li>
            <li><strong>Invitations To An Unhosted Event:</strong> Create invitations for a gathering you'll never host.</li>
            <li><strong>Imaginary Travel Journals:</strong> Record visits to impossible places: cities in clouds, ocean depths...</li>
            <li><strong>Maps Of Forgotten Worlds:</strong> Sketch and describe territories lost in your imagination's geography.</li>
            <li><strong>Museum Of Imaginary Objects:</strong> Curate and describe peculiar items that never were yet ought to be.</li>
            <li><strong>Recipes For Impossibilities:</strong> Share cooking instructions for unrequited love, nostalgia, or perfect days.</li>
            <li><strong>Self-Portrait As A Season:</strong> Capture your spirit through a season.</li>
            <li><strong>Snapshots Of Future Memories:</strong> Write  vignettes from experiences you're yet to have.</li>
            <li><strong>That Which A Pencil Remembers:</strong> Write from the perspective of a pencil recalling everything it's recorded.</li>
            <li><strong>The Stars Envy Earth:</strong> Compose their longing as they gaze down toward our world.</li>
            <li><strong>Things Nature Taught You:</strong> Brief reflections on lessons from trees, rivers, skies, and stones.</li>
            <li><strong>Tiny Stories Of Gigantic Things:</strong> Describe galaxies, mountains, or love in less than 100 words.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>•--♡--•</p>
            ]]></description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Punchy Prose</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/notes/pp</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 06:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://zacharykai.net/notes/pp</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>Punchy Prose</h1>
            <p class="postmeta"><strong>Published</strong>: 22 Feb 2025 | <strong>Updated</strong>: 22 Feb 2025</p>
            <p id="top">Herein you'll find a list of words I watch for in my writing, to replace/remove for stronger prose. Thought you might find it useful!</p>
            <ul>
            <li><a href="#adverbs">Adverbs</a></li>
            <li><a href="#cliches">Cliches</a></li>
            <li><a href="#conjunctions">Conjunction Sentence Starters</a></li>
            <li><a href="#fillers">Filler Words</a></li>
            <li><a href="#generic">Generic Descriptions</a></li>
            <li><a href="#passive">Passive Voice</a></li>
            <li><a href="#redundancies">Redundancies</a></li>
            <li><a href="#telling">Telling Indicators</a></li>
            </ul>
            <h2 id="adverbs">Adverbs</h2>
            <p>I replace these and the accompanining verb with something more impactful.</p>
            <ul>
            <li>abruptly</li>
            <li>absently</li>
            <li>adamantly</li>
            <li>affectionately</li>
            <li>aimlessly</li>
            <li>angrily</li>
            <li>anxiously</li>
            <li>ardently</li>
            <li>arrogantly</li>
            <li>awkwardly</li>
            <li>badly</li>
            <li>bashfully</li>
            <li>bitterly</li>
            <li>blindly</li>
            <li>boldly</li>
            <li>breathlessly</li>
            <li>briskly</li>
            <li>brusquely</li>
            <li>carefully</li>
            <li>casually</li>
            <li>cautiously</li>
            <li>cheerfully</li>
            <li>clearly</li>
            <li>cleverly</li>
            <li>coldly</li>
            <li>comfortably</li>
            <li>confidently</li>
            <li>consciously</li>
            <li>constantly</li>
            <li>coolly</li>
            <li>coyly</li>
            <li>cruelly</li>
            <li>curiously</li>
            <li>darkly</li>
            <li>deeply</li>
            <li>defiantly</li>
            <li>deliberately</li>
            <li>desperately</li>
            <li>determinedly</li>
            <li>diligently</li>
            <li>dimly</li>
            <li>discreetly</li>
            <li>distantly</li>
            <li>dramatically</li>
            <li>dreamily</li>
            <li>eagerly</li>
            <li>easily</li>
            <li>eerily</li>
            <li>elegantly</li>
            <li>emotionally</li>
            <li>emphatically</li>
            <li>endlessly</li>
            <li>evenly</li>
            <li>eventually</li>
            <li>exactly</li>
            <li>excitedly</li>
            <li>expectantly</li>
            <li>expertly</li>
            <li>faintly</li>
            <li>faithfully</li>
            <li>fearfully</li>
            <li>fiercely</li>
            <li>firmly</li>
            <li>fondly</li>
            <li>foolishly</li>
            <li>forcefully</li>
            <li>fortunately</li>
            <li>frantically</li>
            <li>freely</li>
            <li>furiously</li>
            <li>gently</li>
            <li>gladly</li>
            <li>gracefully</li>
            <li>greedily</li>
            <li>grimly</li>
            <li>grudgingly</li>
            <li>happily</li>
            <li>harshly</li>
            <li>hastily</li>
            <li>helplessly</li>
            <li>hesitantly</li>
            <li>hopelessly</li>
            <li>hungrily</li>
            <li>hurriedly</li>
            <li>hysterically</li>
            <li>icily</li>
            <li>impatiently</li>
            <li>impassively</li>
            <li>incessantly</li>
            <li>incredulously</li>
            <li>inevitably</li>
            <li>innocently</li>
            <li>instantly</li>
            <li>intensely</li>
            <li>intentionally</li>
            <li>irritably</li>
            <li>joyfully</li>
            <li>keenly</li>
            <li>lazily</li>
            <li>lightly</li>
            <li>listlessly</li>
            <li>longingly</li>
            <li>loudly</li>
            <li>lovingly</li>
            <li>loyally</li>
            <li>madly</li>
            <li>meaningfully</li>
            <li>mechanically</li>
            <li>menacingly</li>
            <li>miserably</li>
            <li>mockingly</li>
            <li>mysteriously</li>
            <li>naively</li>
            <li>naturally</li>
            <li>nervously</li>
            <li>nonchalantly</li>
            <li>numbly</li>
            <li>obediently</li>
            <li>obnoxiously</li>
            <li>oddly</li>
            <li>ominously</li>
            <li>openly</li>
            <li>painfully</li>
            <li>particularly</li>
            <li>patiently</li>
            <li>patronizingly</li>
            <li>perfectly</li>
            <li>playfully</li>
            <li>politely</li>
            <li>powerfully</li>
            <li>precisely</li>
            <li>proudly</li>
            <li>protectively</li>
            <li>quickly</li>
            <li>quietly</li>
            <li>rapidly</li>
            <li>rashly</li>
            <li>reluctantly</li>
            <li>reproachfully</li>
            <li>resolutely</li>
            <li>restlessly</li>
            <li>reverently</li>
            <li>rigidly</li>
            <li>ruefully</li>
            <li>ruthlessly</li>
            <li>sadly</li>
            <li>sarcastically</li>
            <li>scornfully</li>
            <li>searchingly</li>
            <li>seductively</li>
            <li>selfishly</li>
            <li>sensibly</li>
            <li>seriously</li>
            <li>sharply</li>
            <li>sheepishly</li>
            <li>shrewdly</li>
            <li>shyly</li>
            <li>silently</li>
            <li>sleepily</li>
            <li>slowly</li>
            <li>slyly</li>
            <li>softly</li>
            <li>solemnly</li>
            <li>somberly</li>
            <li>soothingly</li>
            <li>speedily</li>
            <li>stiffly</li>
            <li>strangely</li>
            <li>stubbornly</li>
            <li>suavely</li>
            <li>suddenly</li>
            <li>suspiciously</li>
            <li>swiftly</li>
            <li>sympathetically</li>
            <li>tactfully</li>
            <li>tearfully</li>
            <li>tenderly</li>
            <li>tensely</li>
            <li>thoughtfully</li>
            <li>tightly</li>
            <li>timidly</li>
            <li>tirelessly</li>
            <li>triumphantly</li>
            <li>truthfully</li>
            <li>uneasily</li>
            <li>unexpectedly</li>
            <li>unhappily</li>
            <li>unnaturally</li>
            <li>urgently</li>
            <li>vaguely</li>
            <li>vainly</li>
            <li>valiantly</li>
            <li>venomously</li>
            <li>viciously</li>
            <li>violently</li>
            <li>warily</li>
            <li>warmly</li>
            <li>weakly</li>
            <li>wearily</li>
            <li>wickedly</li>
            <li>wistfully</li>
            <li>woefully</li>
            <li>wildly</li>
            <li>wisely</li>
            <li>wistfully</li>
            <li>wordlessly</li>
            <li>wrathfully</li>
            <li>wretchedly</li>
            </ul>
            <h2 id="cliches">Cliches</h2>
            <p>Time for something more inventive!</p>
            <ul>
            <li>a far cry</li>
            <li>beg to differ</li>
            <li>blood sweat and tears</li>
            <li>bone dry</li>
            <li>built to last</li>
            <li>calm before the storm</li>
            <li>chip in</li>
            <li>deal with it</li>
            <li>deep in thought</li>
            <li>figure it out</li>
            <li>first things first</li>
            <li>force of nature</li>
            <li>foul play</li>
            <li>get lost</li>
            <li>hell to pay</li>
            <li>hit the ground running</li>
            <li>keep it up</li>
            <li>off-kilter</li>
            <li>on the nose</li>
            <li>on track</li>
            <li>on to something</li>
            <li>out of it</li>
            <li>over the edge</li>
            <li>pay attention</li>
            <li>seen better days</li>
            <li>see the light</li>
            <li>sigh of relief</li>
            <li>slipped through my fingers</li>
            <li>thank goodness</li>
            <li>try as i might</li>
            </ul>
            <h2 id="conjunctions">Conjunction Sentence Starters</h2>
            <p>Starting a sentence with these is good, as long as I don't do it too often!</p>
            <ul>
            <li>Also</li>
            <li>And</li>
            <li>As</li>
            <li>Because</li>
            <li>Before</li>
            <li>Besides</li>
            <li>But</li>
            <li>By the time</li>
            <li>For</li>
            <li>If</li>
            <li>Instead</li>
            <li>Once</li>
            <li>Only</li>
            <li>Or</li>
            <li>Since</li>
            <li>Still</li>
            <li>Though</li>
            <li>Until</li>
            <li>When</li>
            <li>Which</li>
            <li>While</li>
            <li>Yet</li>
            </ul>
            <h2 id="fillers">Filler Words</h2>
            <p>Just one word for these: delete!</p>
            <ul>
            <li>absolutely</li>
            <li>actually</li>
            <li>a bit of</li>
            <li>a little</li>
            <li>almost</li>
            <li>altogether</li>
            <li>apparently</li>
            <li>at all</li>
            <li>basically</li>
            <li>barely</li>
            <li>beginning to</li>
            <li>began to</li>
            <li>begun to</li>
            <li>certainly</li>
            <li>clearly</li>
            <li>completely</li>
            <li>continued to</li>
            <li>decide to</li>
            <li>decided to</li>
            <li>definitely</li>
            <li>easily</li>
            <li>even</li>
            <li>exactly</li>
            <li>fairly</li>
            <li>felt like</li>
            <li>finally</li>
            <li>fully</li>
            <li>had to</li>
            <li>happened to</li>
            <li>hardly</li>
            <li>I guess</li>
            <li>I mean</li>
            <li>I suppose</li>
            <li>in order to</li>
            <li>in the middle of</li>
            <li>in the process of</li>
            <li>it was</li>
            <li>just</li>
            <li>just then</li>
            <li>kind of</li>
            <li>like</li>
            <li>literally</li>
            <li>managed to</li>
            <li>maybe</li>
            <li>merely</li>
            <li>nearly</li>
            <li>needed to</li>
            <li>obviously</li>
            <li>okay</li>
            <li>own</li>
            <li>perhaps</li>
            <li>practically</li>
            <li>probably</li>
            <li>quite</li>
            <li>rather</li>
            <li>really</li>
            <li>seem</li>
            <li>seemed</li>
            <li>seemed to</li>
            <li>simply</li>
            <li>slightly</li>
            <li>so</li>
            <li>somewhat</li>
            <li>sort of</li>
            <li>sort of</li>
            <li>started to</li>
            <li>suddenly</li>
            <li>tended to</li>
            <li>that</li>
            <li>the fact that</li>
            <li>then</li>
            <li>there was</li>
            <li>totally</li>
            <li>truly</li>
            <li>tried to</li>
            <li>utterly</li>
            <li>very</li>
            <li>virtually</li>
            <li>wanted to</li>
            <li>was able to</li>
            <li>was going to</li>
            <li>well</li>
            <li>you know</li>
            </ul>
            <h2 id="generic">Generic Descriptions</h2>
            <p>Can I put my vast vocabulary to use?</p>
            <ul>
            <li>big</li>
            <li>good</li>
            <li>great</li>
            <li>large</li>
            <li>look</li>
            <li>looked</li>
            <li>looks</li>
            <li>low</li>
            <li>main</li>
            <li>nice</li>
            <li>powerful</li>
            <li>pretty</li>
            <li>serious</li>
            <li>special</li>
            </ul>
            <h2 id="passive">Passive Voice</h2>
            <p>Let the narrative and characters drive the story, not the sentence.</p>
            <ul>
            <li>affected by</li>
            <li>are being</li>
            <li>are seen</li>
            <li>are thought</li>
            <li>are understood</li>
            <li>can be</li>
            <li>could be</li>
            <li>has been</li>
            <li>have been</li>
            <li>is believed</li>
            <li>is considered</li>
            <li>is expected</li>
            <li>is felt</li>
            <li>is given</li>
            <li>is heard</li>
            <li>is hoped</li>
            <li>is known</li>
            <li>is meant</li>
            <li>is noticed</li>
            <li>is perceived</li>
            <li>is questioned</li>
            <li>is remembered</li>
            <li>is said</li>
            <li>is seen</li>
            <li>is shown</li>
            <li>is supposed</li>
            <li>is taken</li>
            <li>is understood</li>
            <li>it appears</li>
            <li>it has been</li>
            <li>it is believed</li>
            <li>it is considered</li>
            <li>it is expected</li>
            <li>it is known</li>
            <li>it is said</li>
            <li>it is shown</li>
            <li>it seems</li>
            <li>it was</li>
            <li>it will be</li>
            <li>may be</li>
            <li>might be</li>
            <li>must be</li>
            <li>ought to be</li>
            <li>shall be</li>
            <li>should be</li>
            <li>to be</li>
            <li>was being</li>
            <li>was believed</li>
            <li>was considered</li>
            <li>was expected</li>
            <li>was felt</li>
            <li>was given</li>
            <li>was heard</li>
            <li>was hoped</li>
            <li>was known</li>
            <li>was meant</li>
            <li>was noticed</li>
            <li>was perceived</li>
            <li>was questioned</li>
            <li>was remembered</li>
            <li>was said</li>
            <li>was seen</li>
            <li>was shown</li>
            <li>was supposed</li>
            <li>was taken</li>
            <li>was thought</li>
            <li>was understood</li>
            <li>were being</li>
            <li>were believed</li>
            <li>were considered</li>
            <li>were expected</li>
            <li>were felt</li>
            <li>were given</li>
            <li>were heard</li>
            <li>were hoped</li>
            <li>were known</li>
            <li>were meant</li>
            <li>were noticed</li>
            <li>were perceived</li>
            <li>were questioned</li>
            <li>were remembered</li>
            <li>were said</li>
            <li>were seen</li>
            <li>were shown</li>
            <li>were supposed</li>
            <li>were taken</li>
            <li>were thought</li>
            <li>were understood</li>
            <li>will be</li>
            <li>would be</li>
            </ul>
            <h2 id="redundancies">Redundancies</h2>
            <p>I only need one of these words to get the point across.</p>
            <ul>
            <li>absolutely certain</li>
            <li>absolutely essential</li>
            <li>actual experience</li>
            <li>advance notice</li>
            <li>advance planning</li>
            <li>advance preview</li>
            <li>advance warning</li>
            <li>ascend up</li>
            <li>ask a question</li>
            <li>at this moment in time</li>
            <li>at this point in time</li>
            <li>basic essentials</li>
            <li>basic fundamentals</li>
            <li>brief moment</li>
            <li>brief second</li>
            <li>burning fire</li>
            <li>close proximity</li>
            <li>collaborate together</li>
            <li>completely annihilate</li>
            <li>completely destroyed</li>
            <li>completely finished</li>
            <li>consensus of opinion</li>
            <li>continue on</li>
            <li>could possibly</li>
            <li>descend down</li>
            <li>each and every</li>
            <li>end result</li>
            <li>enter in</li>
            <li>exact duplicate</li>
            <li>exact same</li>
            <li>false pretense</li>
            <li>final conclusion</li>
            <li>final outcome</li>
            <li>first and foremost</li>
            <li>foreign imports</li>
            <li>free gift</li>
            <li>frozen ice</li>
            <li>future plans</li>
            <li>general consensus</li>
            <li>green in color</li>
            <li>join together</li>
            <li>kneel down</li>
            <li>lag behind</li>
            <li>major breakthrough</li>
            <li>merge together</li>
            <li>mix together</li>
            <li>mutual cooperation</li>
            <li>mutual respect</li>
            <li>new discovery</li>
            <li>new innovation</li>
            <li>new invention</li>
            <li>past experience</li>
            <li>past history</li>
            <li>personal opinion</li>
            <li>plan ahead</li>
            <li>proceed forward</li>
            <li>rare privilege</li>
            <li>reason why</li>
            <li>repeat again</li>
            <li>return back</li>
            <li>revert back</li>
            <li>rise up</li>
            <li>safe haven</li>
            <li>same exact</li>
            <li>separate apart</li>
            <li>serious crisis</li>
            <li>short summary</li>
            <li>shut down</li>
            <li>small in size</li>
            <li>still remains</li>
            <li>sudden impulse</li>
            <li>sum total</li>
            <li>surrounded on all sides</li>
            <li>unexpected surprise</li>
            <li>usual habit</li>
            <li>very unique</li>
            <li>visible to the eye</li>
            <li>warn in advance</li>
            <li>written down</li>
            </ul>
            <h2 id="telling">Telling Indicators</h2>
            <p>Can I show this so readers can infer it instead? What'd make it more descriptive/engaging?</p>
            <ul>
            <li>could</li>
            <li>feel</li>
            <li>feeling</li>
            <li>felt</li>
            <li>get</li>
            <li>hear</li>
            <li>heard</li>
            <li>knew</li>
            <li>know</li>
            <li>known</li>
            <li>notice</li>
            <li>noticed</li>
            <li>observed</li>
            <li>saw</li>
            <li>see</li>
            <li>tastes</li>
            <li>there</li>
            <li>watched</li>
            </ul>
            <p>•--♡--•</p>
            ]]></description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>One Of A Thousand Ways</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/notes/icfeb25</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hi@zacharykai.net (Zachary Kai)</author>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://zacharykai.net/notes/icfeb25</guid>
            <description>An entry for the February 2025 Indieweb Blog Carnival on affirmations.</description>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[
                <h1>One Of A Thousand Ways</h1>
                <p class="postmeta"><strong>Published</strong>: 7 Feb 2025 | <strong>Updated</strong>: 7 Feb 2025</p>
                <p id="top"></p>
                <p><em>Herein you'll find my entry for the February 2025 <a href="https://indieweb.org/IndieWeb_Carnival">Indieweb Blog Carnival</a>, hosted by <a href="https://artlung.com/">Joe Crawford</a>. The theme is: <a href="https://artlung.com/affirmations-ic/">affirmations</a>.</em> <em>If you have a site, why not also participate?</em></p>
                <p>While much gets written about affirmations and their positive benefits... It's never made it passed my intense skepticism. Why should I repeat to myself things which might not be true?</p>
                <p>I always thought they had more impact if they came from others, but depending on the outside world to receive them... It's out of your hands. </p>
                <p>Writing and reciting your own is a way of taking back control.</p>
                <p>Besides, isn't it akin to a gratitude list or journal? </p>
                <p>Call it trite, overly positive, unrealistic, or strange...</p>
                <p>At its heart, it's just one of a thousand ways of cultivating joy.</p>
                <p>•--♡--•</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>In Search Of Lost... Editions | January 2025</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/newsletter/jan25</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hi@zacharykai.net (Zachary Kai)</author>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://zacharykai.net/newsletter/jan25</guid>
            <description>Herein you'll find an archived edition of my monthly newsletter from Jan 2025. Hope you enjoy reading!</description>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[ <h1>In Search Of Lost... Editions</h1>
                <p class="postmeta"><strong>Published</strong>: 5 Feb 2025 | <strong>Updated</strong>: 5 Feb 2025</p>
                <p id="top">Herein you'll find an archived edition of my monthly newsletter: Jan 2025. Hope you enjoy!</p>
                <h2>Field Notes</h2>
                <p>What was supposed to be the January (and inaugural edition) is being published today! However, for posterity's sake, I'll only cover happenings of interest from January.</p>
                <p>I shall return later this month with February's issue.</p>
                <p>And please bear with me as I figure out the formatting for the issues.</p>
                <p>I want to ensure it's a record for my own existence, but also pleasurable and useful for you! If you have any suggestions or advice, please email me.</p>
                <p>I've achieved much in and around work this month!</p>
                <p>A little writing and reading, a few lovely email exchanges, but most has been admin: setting up my Ko-Fi and Payhip stores, compiling stories for Echoes Of Distant Stars, my first short story collection, preparing The Mara Files for re-publication, and sorting out my publishing process.</p>
                <p>Digital cleaning and mending, if you will!</p>
                <p>On the last day of 2024, I posted my goals for the upcoming year. So far, I've achieved two (setting up my Ko-Fi store, launching my monthly newsletter.) Onwards!</p>
                <h2>Links & Tidbits</h2>
                <ul>
                <li>Started attending Homebrew Website Club events, hosted as part of the Indieweb. If you're interested in making websites for fun, why not join? They're lovely folk!</li>
                <li>Published the following notes on my site:
                <ul>
                <li>Mildura Zine Fair 2024 Reflections</li>
                <li>Notes From An Are.na Workshop: Channel As Gift</li>
                </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Watched the livestream of Amanda Montell's author talk, facilitated by the Library Speakers Consortium. Also want to watch the replay of Seth Fishman's.</li>
                <li>Updates of interest from the changelog:
                <ul>
                <li>Added a page to archive my newsletter editions, and another to list my books.</li>
                <li>Created, then linked my Indieweb Wiki page in the footer.</li>
                </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Books I enjoyed reading:
                <ul>
                <li>I Shall Never Fall In Love by Hari Conner</li>
                <li>Dark Wire by Joseph Cox</li>
                <li>The Wrath Of The Triple Goddess by Rick Riordan</li>
                <li>Disability Visibility by Alice Wong</li>
                <li>Letters To Half-Moon Street by Sarah Wallace</li>
                </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Links discovered in January:
                <ul>
                <li>52 Things I Learned In 2024 by Kent Hendricks</li>
                <li>Alee Steele's Site</li>
                <li>Blog Inspiration by Robert Birming</li>
                <li>Blog Like a Painter by Robert Birming</li>
                <li>Cyber Nymph Garden</li>
                <li>Hardcode Soft Skills by Dave Rupert</li>
                <li>Laurel Schwulst's Site</li>
                <li>Let A Website Be A Worry Stone by Ethan Marcotte</li>
                <li>Knitted Camouflage by Joseph Ford</li>
                <li>Syllabus For Taking An Internet Walk by Spencer Chang & Kristoffer Tjalve</li>
                <li>Sort Out Your Life! 100 Tiny Tricks To Help With Everything From Digital Overwhelm To Lumpy Sugar And Unpaid Bills by Emma Beddington for <em>The Guardian</em></li>
                </ul>
                </li>
                </ul>
                <p>•--♡--•</p>
                ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Blog Questions Challenge 2025</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/notes/blogqna25</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hi@zacharykai.net (Zachary Kai)</author>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://zacharykai.net/notes/blogqna25</guid>
            <description>Saw many folks answering these questions, so I thought, why not answer them too! If you have a site, please do also if so inclined.</description>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[ <h1>Blog Questions Challenge 2025</h1>
                <p id="top">Saw many folks answering these questions, so I thought, why not answer them too! If you have a site, please do also if so inclined. (Kudos to Annie Mueller's <a href="https://anniemueller.com/posts/blog-question-challenge-2025" target="_blank">post</a> for pushing me over the edge.)</p>
                <h2>Why Did You Start Blogging In The First Place?</h2>
                <p>I started writing on the internet to capture my notes from events and archive my existence, in the hopes of creating a time capsule for myself and something (hopefully) useful for others.</p>
                <h2>What Platform Are You Using To Manage Your Blog, And Why Do You Use It?</h2>
                <p>I'm not using any platform! When creating this site in March 2024, my aim was as simple as possible. So I use static HTML files, styled with CSS, and uploaded to my host's file manager.</p>
                <p>While I sometimes wish it were 'easier' to add written works and update, it's worth it for the simplicity, the fast-loading times, and the ease of editing/debugging.</p>
                <h2>Have You Blogged On Other Platforms Before?</h2>
                <p>Indeed! I've used WordPress for work since 2016, and currently my book blog, <a href="https://roadlessread.com">Road Less Read</a> uses it. I want to convert that site to static HTML, but haven't made the time for it yet.</p>
                <h2>How Do You Write Your Posts?</h2>
                <p>When I'm taking notes at events, usually I do it on paper, then transcribe directly into a HTML file. Lately, though, I've started writing in markdown in Obsidian, and using an online tool to convert that to HTML. Makes the drafting process far more pleasant!</p>
                <p>From there, I proof the HTML file, upload it to my host via FileZilla, record the addition in the <a href="https://zacharykai.net/changelog">changelog</a> and the <a href="https://zacharykai.net/sitemap">sitemap</a>, and update the <a href="https://zacharykai.net/assets/rss.xml">RSS file</a>. And yes, I do this all manually!</p>
                <h2>When Do You Feel Most Inspired To Write?</h2>
                <p>Good question! Inspiration only seems to come for fiction. Until now, and aside from journaling, it'd never occurred to me to write 'personal non-fiction or essays.' I'm still new to this!</p>
                <h2>Do You Normally Publish Immediately After Writing, Or Do You Let It Simmer?</h2>
                <p>I haven't written enough here to give a definite answer, but mostly I do two proofreads (once with software, the second time manually) before I publish.</p>
                <p>If you've discovered a typo or grammatical error in my work, please, <a href="mailto:hi@zacharykai.net">email me</a>!</p>
                <h2>What's Your Favorite Post On Your Blog?</h2>
                <p>Granted, I've only published nine times as of the time of writing, but so far, it'd be answering <a href="https://zacharykai.net/notes/proust">Proust's Questionnaire</a>. I was alerted to the idea browsing Xanthe Tynehorne's lovely site and finding <a href="https://satyrs.eu/proust">their answers</a>. If you have a site, why not answer it too? (Please <a href="mailto:hi@zacharykai.net">email me</a> if you do!)</p>
                <h2>Any Future Plans For The Blog?</h2>
                <p>Publishing more often! And with a wider breadth of subjects. Writing to learn, think through ideas, and find folks who enjoy what I find fascinating.</p>
                <p>•--♡--•</p> ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Mildura Zine Fair 2024 Reflections</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/notes/mzf24</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hi@zacharykai.net (Zachary Kai)</author>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://zacharykai.net/notes/mzf24</guid>
            <description>Herein you'll find my short reflections from attending the Mildura Zine Fair in July 2024: my first zine fair and the first time I'd ever printed out my zines.</description>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[ <h1>Mildura Zine Fair 2024 Reflections</h1>
                <p id="top">Herein you'll find my short reflections from attending the Mildura Zine Fair in July 2024: my first zine fair and the first time I'd ever printed out my zines.</p>
                <ul>
                <li>Don't sell yourself short. People will like your zines!</li>
                <li>Bring zines to trade as an excuse for interesting conversations.</li>
                <li>Make use of the resources you have around you.</li>
                <li>Make zines on paper and clean them up and arrange them digitally.</li>
                <li>Print folded zines double-sided so there's an interesting surprise on the non-content side.</li>
                <li>You can sew bindings for zines with a sewing machine.</li>
                <li>Small Zine Volcano accepts free zines for distribution in Melbourne and surrounds.</li>
                <li>Photocopying A4 (single-sided black and white) is cheapest.</li>
                <li>Zines can be anything and everything!</li>
                </ul>
                <p>•--♡--•</p> ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Goals For 2025</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/notes/25goals</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hi@zacharykai.net (Zachary Kai)</author>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://zacharykai.net/notes/25goals</guid>
            <description>Herein you'll find my goals for 2025: what I'd like to achieve. Recorded here to remain accountable to myself!</description>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[ <h1>Goals For 2025</h1>
                <p id="top">Herein you'll find my goals for 2025: what I'd like to achieve. Recorded here to remain accountable to myself! Inspired by Joanna Penn and her <a href="https://www.thecreativepenn.com/2024/12/30/review-of-my-2024-creative-and-business-goals-with-joanna-penn/" target="_blank">yearly reviews</a> and <a href="https://www.thecreativepenn.com/2025/01/01/my-2025-creative-and-business-goals-with-joanna-penn/" target="_blank">goals</a>.</p>
                <p><strong>Table Of Contents</strong></p>
                <ul>
                <li><a href="#lunaseeker-press">Lunaseeker Press</a></li>
                <li><a href="#personal">Personal</a></li>
                <li><a href="#tracking">Tracking</a></li>
                </ul>
                <h2 id="lunaseeker-press">Lunaseeker Press</h2>
                <h3>Developing</h3>
                <ul>
                <li>Convert Road Less Read to static HTML.</li>
                <li>Set up my Ko-Fi store with all my short stories, novels, and zines.</li>
                </ul>
                <h3>Publishing</h3>
                <ul>
                <li>Launch monthly newsletter.</li>
                <li>Produce and publish 1 new zine quarterly.</li>
                <li>Re-release <em>The Mara Files</em>.</li>
                <li>Research the traditional publishing process.</li>
                <li>Write and publish two articles monthly: one for this site and one for Road Less Read.</li>
                </ul>
                <h3>Submitting</h3>
                <ul>
                <li>Submit to two literary magazines/anthologies per month.</li>
                <li>Submit this site to web directories.</li>
                </ul>
                <h3>Writing</h3>
                <ul>
                <li>Finish the <em>Don't Burn Too Bright</em> manuscript.</li>
                <li>Begin and complete the first draft of a new book (to look at traditional publishing.)</li>
                </ul>
                <h2 id="personal">Personal</h2>
                <ul>
                <li>Attend one creative event monthly.</li>
                <li>Make a journal entry every evening.</li>
                <li>Listen to five new songs monthly.</li>
                <li>Read two good fiction books monthly.</li>
                </ul>
                <h2 id="tracking">Tracking</h2>
                <ul>
                <li>Create a public progress tracker on this site.</li>
                <li>Do a quarterly goal review and adjustment.</li>
                <li>Record monthly progress updates via the newsletter.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>•--♡--•</p> ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Notes From An Are.na Workshop: Channel As Gift</title>
            <link>https://zacharykai.net/notes/agwdec24</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hi@zacharykai.net (Zachary Kai)</author>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://zacharykai.net/notes/agwdec24</guid>
            <description>In late December 2024, I attended an Are.na Channel As Gift workshop hosted by Laurel Schwulst. Such a fascinating idea! These are my notes from attending.</description>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[ <h1>Notes From An Are.na Workshop: Channel As Gift (21 Dec 2024)</h1>
                <p id="top">In late December 2024, I attended an Are.na Channel As Gift workshop hosted by Laurel Schwulst. Such a fascinating idea! These are my notes from attending.</p>
                <ul>
                <li>Gifting as a verb is more nourishing than the noun.</li>
                <li>Gift giving is often separated as its own love language, but you could argue that all other love languages involve the giving of a gift.</li>
                <li>Attention and time are the ingredients for a good gift. Being a good gift giver is about listening, appreciating, and considering. You make connections between disparate things and the people you love.</li>
                <li>Living with the intention of generosity is gift giving at its core. Even something as simple as an email can be a gift: putting in effort shows you care.</li>
                <li>A wonderful gift is a Venn diagram of what you and the recipient enjoy. A moment of connection often becomes more important than the material thing.</li>
                <li>Thoughtful digital gifts: a memory capsule of photos, a playlist, a reader of recommended articles or books, summarizing your shared existence, an imaginary museum, reasons why they're loved, and a to-do list of fun activities</li>
                <li>Gifting as an infinite game is a constant back-and-forth, a way of life.</li>
                </ul>
                <p><strong>Bibliography</strong></p>
                <ul>
                <li><a href="https://laurelschwulst.com/" target="_blank">Laurel Schwulst's Site</a></li>
                <li><a href="https://www.are.na/laurel-schwulst/channel-as-gift" target="_blank">The Workshop's Are.na Channel</a></li>
                <li><a href="https://www.are.na/editorial/gifting-guides" target="_blank">The Workshop's Ethos</a></li>
                </ul>
                <p>•--♡--•</p> ]]>
            </content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>